Fate of one. Future of all.
Fantastic Beasts: The Crimes of Grindelwald is a fantasy,
adventure film directed by David Yates.
Gellert Grindelwald has escaped imprisonment and has begun gathering followers
to his cause—elevating wizards above all non-magical beings.
The only one capable of putting a stop to him is the wizard he
once called his closest friend, Albus Dumbledore.
However, Dumbledore will need to seek help from the wizard who had thwarted Grindelwald once before, his
former student Newt Scamander, who agrees to help, unaware of the dangers that lie ahead.
Lines are drawn as love and loyalty are tested, even among the truest
friends and family, in an increasingly divided wizarding world.
Newt Scamander, played by Eddie Redmayne.
Tina Goldstein, played by Katherine Waterston.
Jacob Kowalski, played by Dan Fogler.
Queenie Goldstein, played by Alison Sudol.
Grindelwald, played by Johnny Depp.
Albus Dumbledore, played by Jude Law.
Fantastic Beasts: The Crimes of Grindelwald is a 2018 fantasy
film directed by David Yates and written by J.
The sequel to Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them (2016), it is the second instalment in the
Fantastic Beasts film series and the tenth overall in the Wizarding World franchise.
It features an ensemble cast including Eddie Redmayne, Katherine Waterston, Dan Fogler, Alison Sudol, Ezra Miller,
Zoë Kravitz, Callum Turner, Claudia Kim, William Nadylam, Kevin Guthrie, Jude Law, and Johnny Depp.
Set in 1927, it follows Newt Scamander and Albus Dumbledore as they attempt to take down the dark
wizard Gellert Grindelwald while facing new threats in a more divided wizarding world.
A second Fantastic Beasts film was announced in October 2014, and Rowling
confirmed in July 2016 that she had completed the script.
Depp was cast in November 2016, causing some controversy due to
domestic violence allegations made against him.
Law signed on in April 2017.
Principal photography began in July 2017 at Warner Bros.
Studios, Leavesden, in England.
Filming also took place in London, Switzerland, and
Paris, and wrapped in December 2017.
Fantastic Beasts: The Crimes of Grindelwald premiered in Paris on 8 November 2018, and was released
theatrically in the United Kingdom and United States on 16 November 2018, by Warner Bros.
It grossed $654.9 million worldwide, making it the
tenth highest-grossing film of 2018.
It became the lowest-grossing instalment of the Wizarding World franchise upon release, which it remained
until the release of its sequel, Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore, in 2022.
It received generally mixed reviews from critics, as it was viewed to have been filled
with too many characters and "overburdened" with sequel-dependent details.
At the 72nd British Academy Film Awards, the film was nominated for
Best Production Design and Best Special Visual Effects.
The sequel, Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of
Dumbledore, was released in April 2022.
The film explores themes of witch, new york city,
paris, france, magic, school of witchcraft.